<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>compilation on Software adventures and thoughts</title><link>http://blog.ralch.com/tags/compilation/</link><description>Recent content in compilation on Software adventures and thoughts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 11:04:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.ralch.com/tags/compilation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sharing Golang packages to C and Go</title><link>http://blog.ralch.com/articles/golang-sharing-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 11:04:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://blog.ralch.com/articles/golang-sharing-libraries/</guid><description>The latest Go 1.5 version is out. As part of the new features, Go compiler can compile packages as a shared libraries.
It accepts -buildmode argument that determines how a package is compiled. These are the following options:
archive: Build the listed non-main packages into .a files. Packages named main are ignored. c-archive: Build the listed main package, plus all packages it imports, into a C archive file. c-shared: Build the listed main packages, plus all packages that they import, into C shared libraries.</description></item><item><title>Conditional compilation in Golang</title><link>http://blog.ralch.com/articles/golang-conditional-compilation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 08:40:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://blog.ralch.com/articles/golang-conditional-compilation/</guid><description>When developing Go package or application that depends on specific features of the underlying platform or architecture it is often necessary to use a specialised implementation.
There are two parts of Go conditional compilation system, which we will now explore in more detail.
Build constraints A build constraints (known as build tags) is an optional top line comment that starts with
// +build package api Declaration of build constraints follows the following rules:</description></item></channel></rss>